In the last lecture we used updateObject, this utility function.
Son derste, updateObject, bu yardmc program ilevini kullandk.
Now there's one other feature we also share across multiple files and hence it would make sense to outsource
imdi birden fazla dosyada paylatmz bir baka zellik daha var ve bu yzden d kaynak
it,
kullanmak
I'm talking about the validation logic,
mantkl gelecektir, ben dorulama mant,
checkValidity.
checkValidity hakknda konuuyorum.
It's the same method in the auth container and the contact data container
Bu, auth kapsaycsnda ve iletiim veri kabnda ayn yntemdir, bu nedenle
so it makes sense to grab checkValidity and put it into our shared folder into the utility.js file
checkValidity'i kapmak ve paylalan klasrmze yardmc programa koymak anlamldr. rnein js dosyas, ayrca yeni
for example,
bir
you could also create a new validation.js file, whatever you want.
dorulama da oluturabilirsiniz. js dosyas, ne istersen.
So I'll use checkValidity,
Bu yzden checkValidity kullanacam, tabiki
of course it's no longer a method here instead it's a function
artk bir yntem deil, bunun yerine bir fonksiyon var, bu
so let's export it as an arrow function which expects two arguments.
yzden onu iki argman bekler bir ok fonksiyonu olarak ihra edelim.
This is how simple you restructure it, export const equal sign and an error
Bu, onu yeniden yaplandrarak basitletirir, const eittir iaretini ve bir hatay da aktarr
and inside the function, nothing has to change because we're only working with the function arguments
ve ilev iinde hibir ey deimez, nk biz sadece iyi bir ileve sahip olmamz
in there, as we should in a good function.
gerektii gibi, orada ilev argmanlaryla alacaz.
So we can now use checkValidity in the contact data and the auth container, let's start the auth container
Bu yzden, imdi irtibat verilerinde ve auth konteynrnda checkValidity'i kullanabiliriz, hadi auth kapsaycsn balatalm,
because there I just removed it
nk onu yeni kaldrdm
and for that, I'll import it from the utility file where I also imported updateObject.
ve bunun iin ben de updateObject 'i de ithal ettiim yardmc programdan ithal edeceim.
And I now simply need to replace my call to this.checkValidity with just checkValidity which I just
Ve imdi sadece arlarm deitirmem gerekiyor. Sadece ithalat ekledim sadece checkValidity ile checkValidity ve
added the import to and that's all
hepsi bu ve bu dosya
and this makes this file a bit leaner and removes this unnecessary code duplication.
biraz daha yaln yapar ve bu gereksiz kod oaltma kaldrr.
Now let's do the same for the contact data,
imdi iletiim verileri iin
there I'll also import checkValidity from the utility file and then in the place where I do use it
ayn eyi yapalm, orada da checkValidity'i yardmc program dosyasndan ie aktaracam ve
with this checkValidity, I will simply call just checkValidity
daha sonra bu checkValidity ile kullandm yerde sadece checkValidity'i arayacam ve elbette
and of course that means I can now remove the checkValidity method.
ki imdi kaldrabileceim anlamna gelir checkValidity yntemi.
Let's save both files and let's see if this still works.
Her iki dosyay da kaydedelim ve bunun hala ie yarayp yaramadn grelim.
If we go back to the application and we start building a burger,
Uygulamaya geri dnersek ve bir burger yapmaya balarsak,
let's have a look at our contact data there.
oradaki iletiim bilgilerimize bir bakalm.
If I empty this, validation still seems to work fine
Bunu boaltrsam, dorulama hala iyi alyor gibi grnyor, bu yzden
so everything still works
her ey hala alyor,
but now of course, we greatly improved the code by outsourcing checkValidity into its own file.
ancak imdi elbette, checkValidity'i kendi dosyasna d kaynak kullanarak kodu byk lde gelitirdik.